Nick Pounders

226 Hiawassee Dr. Woodstock, GA 30188

Phone: 404-520-0033 e-mail: nickpounders@gmail.com

Professional Objective

Dedicated individual with a proactive approach looking to join the software development team wherein I can apply education, long-term career aspirations and experience in a challenging technical position.

Skills Summary

Upcoming Computer Science graduate offering a strong foundation in software engineering and programming principles. Currently responsible for supporting projects and various engineering tasks within Product Development or Process Development within the Research & Development team working on medical devices. Experience in the application, use, training, and troubleshooting of proprietary software platforms. Additional experience with installing, configuring, and troubleshooting electrical and mechanical systems.

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Kennesaw State University Current GPA 3.78/4.00 – December 2018

Relevant Course Work: Programing Principals I&II, Intro to Database Systems, Advanced Database, Data Structures, Linux/Unix Administration, Operating Systems, Internet Programming, Intro to Software Engineering, Computer Org and Arc, Software Architecture and Design, Operating Systems, Software System Requirements, Concepts of Programming Languages.

Associate of Applied Science, Electronic and Computer Engineering Technology, Chattahoochee Technical College GPA 3.97/4.00 – 2011.

Honors/Awards:

Upsilon Pi Epsilon Honor Society Member - International Honor Society for the Computing and Information Disciplines.

Boston Scientific 2016 Engineering Excellence Award

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

Platforms and Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Node.is, SQL Server, My SQL, Windows, OS X, Linux

Other: Microsoft Office, Git, Microsoft Visio, IntelliJ, SolidWorks

Professional Experience

Boston Scientific formerly EndoChoice, Alpharetta, GA November 2013 – Present

R&D Specialist

- Development of verification and validation test methods, protocols, and reports in an FDA regulated industry.
- Project support by performing various tasks in relation to product design, fixture design, materials testing, prototype building, FMEA analysis, design reviews, etc.
- Calibration Management System Administrator: coordinate all activities for location to ensure all equipment stays in a qualified calibrated state.

FLIR Integrated System, Alpharetta, GA

July 2012 – November 2013

Electrical/Mechanical Technician

RE/MAX Regional Services, Alpharetta, GA

May 2011 - June 2012

Technical Services Coordinator

- Provided day-to-day contact for users, actively sought out resolution to user problems with designated product/ service lines and trained numerous remote offices on company provided software platforms.
- Provided office network support for servers, computers/laptop, printer/copier, backup routines, virus protection etc.
- Salesforce.com Administrator.